smart.com.ph 2018-05-31

# Privacy Policy - Smart Communications

######  **Our Approach to Privacy**

######  To provide you with the best customer experience, Smart is committed to protecting your privacy and staying transparent with the way we handle your personal information.  For this we have designed a privacy policy that will help you understand how we collect, use, store, share and protect the personal information you have entrusted us. 

###### **Privacy Policy**

###### Our privacy policy values and protects your personal information under the Data Privacy Act of 2012 and the laws of the Philippines. Personal information simply means any information or data that can be used to distinguish, identify or contact you.  

Our Privacy Policy explains:  
• Why we collect personal information  
• What kind information we collect  
• Where we get these information  
• Who we share your information with  
• How we protect your information  
• Your choices, including how you can check and update any personal information we have about you  
• What happens if there are changes in our privacy policy

As a condition for use of our products and services, you are consenting to the Privacy Policy of Smart Communications, Inc. (we, our, us) and its  subsidiaries, affiliates,  and subcontractors; and the collection, use, access, transfer, storage and processing of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

###### **Why we collect personal information  **

###### To improve our products and services, it is important that we collect, use, process and analyze your personal information when it is reasonable and necessary.  When we can, we aggregate and anonymize this information such that you are never identified as an individual. [Aggregating simply means presenting information in segments or categories like age groups; anonymizing means removing personally identifiable information from the data].  

In particular, we are using your information to:

1\. Manage your account, provide customer care activities, monitor the quality and security of the network, train our staff, provide services timely and efficiently, and ensure your fair and lawful use of the products and services provided by Smart;

2\. Send commercial and promotional advertisements, [loyalty and rewards offers](https://www.research.net/r/smartcorporate), [surveys](https://www.research.net/r/smartcorporate), customer care and aftersales communications, and other broadcast push messages;

3\. Share your personal data with third-party content providers or other third-party services for which you sign up;

4\. Conduct analysis for research and marketing initiatives, including the generation of anonymized or non-personally identifiable location and mobility data to show footfall, location patterns, crowd density, and other information that may be relevant for marketing purposes;

######  5\. Generate statistical insights based on usage/network information to assist the Government in planning for healthcare, disaster, and other similar initiatives;

######  6\. Run credit scoring programs and initiatives, including but not limited to, providing information to the Credit Information Corporation in accordance to Republic Act No. 9501, otherwise known as the Credit Information System Act; and

######  7\. Perform such other processing or disclosure that may be required under law or regulations.

######  In cases where your separate and full consent is given, we are also processing your personal data to:

1\. Create your personal profile based on your interests, preferences, mobility patterns from physical locations that you may visit, and other information that may be relevant for marketing and market research purposes;

######    
2\. Share your personal profile based on your interests, preferences, and mobility patterns from physical locations that you may visit, to our business partners and third-party service providers;

3\. Compute your credit score based on data collected internally within the PLDT Group and its subsidiaries and affiliates, and share your credit score to third-parties to whom you specifically instruct us to share your credit score; and

4\. Send you information on offers, promotions, and advertisements from our business partners and third-party service providers. 

###### **What type of information we collect**

###### We collect information to provide better services to all of our users – from figuring out basic details like what postpaid plan is best for you, to more complex things like which related services and digital content you’ll find interesting & useful.  This includes information such as:

###### **Who you are**

###### • Basic personal information like your name, date of birth, gender, nationality, address, and identity supporting documents such as SSS or passport numbers. You can check what we know about you by making a request to the Smart Data Privacy Officer through the contact details provided below;  
• Your credit card, bank and payment details; and  
• Your contact details like billing address, telephone number, mobile phone number, email address;

######  What type of information we collect

######  We collect information to provide better services to all of our users – from figuring out basic details like what postpaid plan is best for you, to more complex things like which related services and digital content you’ll find interesting & useful.  This includes information such as:

###### **What you use our network for**

###### • Your mobile phone location (to enable connection to our network to make calls, SMS and/or access our data services);  
• Your call, text, data and billing records including any other products and services you use like our [apps](https://help.smart.com.ph/mysmartapp?utm_campaign=mysmart-mobileapp&utm_source=sms-blast&utm_term=download), [website](https://smart.com.ph/corporate), [self-care channels](https://my.smart.com.ph/) as well as the date and time of use, duration, where you use them and how much it costs;   
• The device you use when to access our Products and Services (such as your mobile handset, your computer system and platform) to customize our service for you; and  
• No, we don’t look at the content of your text messages and we don’t listen to your calls, unless you’re talking to our hotline.

**What you do with your Smart Account**  
• This includes when and how much you reload or pay your bills; and  
• How often you access your account and why.

######  **Where we get these information  **

######  There are several ways that we may obtain your Personal Data. The process can be done through [](https://smart.com.ph/corporate#)market research activiteand via our websites and [apps](https://help.smart.com.ph/mysmartapp?utm_campaign=mysmart-mobileapp&utm_source=sms-blast&utm_term=download). Other sources include our subsidiaries and 

###### affiliates, and our business partners and third-party service providers.

###### **Information that you personally give us**

######  Most of the personal information we have are those that you have given us yourself. You provide us personal information when you:

######  • Apply for subscription to our services by filling out a Service Application Form online, in one of our stores, or provide personal information to one of our TeleSales representative;

######    
• Get in touch with us to ask about something, file a complaint or request for service;

• Take part in our research and surveys; and/or

######    
• When you apply for a job with us.

###### **Information we collect during our relationship with you**

###### We also collect information as you use our products & services, like when you:  
• Use our networks - whether it is mobile, Wi-Fi, or other channels;

• Pay your bill or [purchase add-on products and services](https://store.smart.com.ph/);

• Use our [apps](https://help.smart.com.ph/mysmartapp?utm_campaign=mysmart-mobileapp&utm_source=sms-blast&utm_term=download), websites and [self-service channels](http://my.smart.com.ph/); and

######  • Join our promos, prize raffles or reward & loyalty programs

###### **  
Information we collect from other sources**

###### We also collect information from commercially or publicly available sources like published directories and public documents. We may also obtain your personal information from third parties (credit agencies) and from other sources which you have given consent for the disclosure of such information relating to you and where otherwise lawfully permitted.

###### **  
Information we collect during our relationship with you**

###### We also collect information as you use our products & services, like when you:  
• Use our networks - whether it is mobile, Wi-Fi, or other channels;

######    
• Pay your bill or purchase add-on products and services;

• Use our apps, websites and self-service channels; and

######    
• Join our promos, prize raffles or reward & loyalty programs

###### **  
Information we collect from other sources**

######  We also collect information from commercially or publicly available sources like published directories and public documents. We may also obtain your personal information from third parties (credit agencies) and from other sources which you have given consent for the disclosure of such information relating to you and where otherwise lawfully permitted.

###### **  
How we protect your information**

######  The integrity, confidentiality and security of your information are particularly important to us. That’s why we strictly enforce our privacy policy within the company and we have implemented technological, organizational and physical security measures that are designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, use, alteration and disclosure.  We also put in effect safeguards such as:

1\. We keep and protect your information using a secured server behind a firewall, encryption and security controls;

######    
2\. We restrict access to your information only to qualified and authorized personnel who hold your information with strict confidentiality;

3\. We undergo regular audit and rigorous testing of our infrastructure’s security protocols to ensure your data is always protected; and

4\. We let you update your information securely to keep our records accurate.

We will retain your personal data throughout the subscription of our products and services, and for a maximum period of five (5) years afterwards.

Your choices, including how you can check and update any personal information we have about you.  
You are afforded certain rights in relation to your personal data under the Data Privacy Act of 2012, which includes the right to object to processing, the right to access your data, the right to modify of inaccurate data, and the right to erasure or blocking of data. 

If you wish to have access to your personal information in our records; or you think that such personal information we have of you is incomplete, not up-to-date, or otherwise inaccurate, you may get in touch with our Data Privacy Officer through the contact details provided below.

###### **Our Contact Details:**

###### Smart Data Privacy Officer   
Mr. Jose Alvin G. Gendrano  
6799 Ayala Ave., Makati City, 1226, Philippines  
Email: [dataprivacyoffice@smart.com.ph](http://dataprivacyoffice@smart.com.ph/)  
Smart Hotline Nos. *888 or (02)888-1111

###### **What happens when there are changes in this policy**

###### From time to time, Smart may change this privacy policy to comply with government and regulatory requirements; to adapt to new technologies and protocols; to align with industry practices; or for other legitimate purposes. You will always be provided notice if these changes are material and, if we are required by law, we will also obtain your consent.    
________________________________________

You can modify your privacy settings at your convenience. Visit  <http://smart.com.ph/privacy>. 

#### **Website Privacy Policy**

###### The policies below are applicable to the Web site and affiliate sites of Smart Communications, Inc. (SMART) found at [www.smart.com.ph](http://smart.com.ph/corporate) . Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our Web site. They do not apply to information that you may submit to us offline or to Web sites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or may have link through us. 

###### By visiting our Web site, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Web site.

###### SMART collects personal information, voluntarily submitted by visitors to the Web site, which enables us to respond to requests for publications, distribute e-newsletters, process employment inquiries and respond to requests for more information or assistance. SMART adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Web site. Except as disclosed below, we do not sell, barter, give away, rent or permit anyone outside of SMART to use your personal information.

###### We occasionally use third-party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners to perform functions such as creative design, marketing, analytics, programming, site maintenance, providing customer service, etc., on our behalf. These entities have access to the personal information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of any personal information collected from the Web site. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering these data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Web site. 

###### We may also use or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to   
(a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website;   
(b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Web site or our users, and   
(c) act under emergency circumstances to protect our safety and security and those of our affiliates, agents and the users of the Web site or the public in general.

###### SMART also collects anonymous information to help us tailor the Web site to visitor interests and concerns. We use "cookies" to help us understand which parts of our Web site are the most popular, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. The information that is gathered through cookies is used solely to assist in improving Web site design and function. This Web site is functional without the retention of cookies. You may elect to block cookies from this site through your browser settings. SMART strives to protect the transmission of any information submitted by visitors. SMART does not warrant that transmission of data will be completely secured, and any and all submissions are at the visitor's risk.

###### This Web site may contain links to sites operated by third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information gathered through these other Web sites. 

###### Please remember that any information that you may share in public areas, such as message boards or feedback sections, becomes public, and therefore this Privacy Policy does not apply to any information you choose to make public. Please be careful about what you disclose, and do not post any personal information that you expect to keep private. 

###### The Web site is published in the Republic of the Philippines and is subject to laws of the Republic of the Philippines. If you are located in a country outside the Republic of the Philippines and voluntarily submit personal information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the Republic of the Philippines. SMART shall not be liable under any circumstances for damages resulting from use of information collected from visitors to the site.

###### SMART may change this Privacy Policy to reflect, among others, changes in the way we collect visitor information.

###### Questions and comments should be directed to this [email address](https://help.smart.com.ph/helpticket/mysmart). 

###### Last updated: January 21, 2009
